<Page xmlns="http://schemas.nativescript.org/tns.xsd"
	 xmlns:parallax="nativescript-parallax"
	loaded="pageLoaded">
  	<parallax:ParallaxView bounce="true" controlsToFade="headerLabel,headerLabel2">
		<parallax:Header class="header-template" dropShadow="true">
			<Label id="headerLabel" text="Parallax"></Label>
			<Label id="headerLabel2" text="Component"></Label>
		</parallax:Header>
		<parallax:Anchored class="anchor" dropShadow="false">
			<Label id="titleLabel" text="Parallax Template"></Label>
		</parallax:Anchored>
		<parallax:Content class="body-template">
                        <Label textWrap="true" text="n his important book, Out of Print: Newspapers, Journalism and the Business of News in the Digital Age (2013), George Brock, a veteran journalist who is currently Professor of Journalism at City University London, identifies verification, sense making, bearing witness, and investigation as “the irreducible core of what can be distinguished as journalism and… the basis of the trust on which it relies.” He predicts that these four core tasks will be “the foundation on which journalism in the 21st century is going to be rebuilt.”

Over the past half-century, there has been an ebb and flow of investigative journalism across the world, including of course India. Related to this, but separate from it, there has been an ebb and flow of public engagement with the results of investigative journalism, in response to larger events, trends, and issues in politics, economy, culture, society, and international relations.

But what is investigative journalism?

When it comes to definition, there is a surprising lack of agreement among practitioners and scholars in the field. Let us agree on the proposition that investigative journalism is the discipline of digging deep and bringing to light verified facts about wrongdoing, or about a matter of significance, which are sought to be covered up or are otherwise inaccessible to the public. But getting the facts right only lays the foundation for investigative work, which will not be worth very much if the reporter does not get the ‘meaning of events right.’

Gabriel García Márquez, who started out as a journalist and remained engaged with journalism and journalism education all his life, has a clear view on the central role of investigation; interestingly, it is a viewpoint shared by many old-world journalists. In a wonderful little meditation titled “Journalism: The Best Job in the World,” delivered in Los Angeles in 1996, the great writer puts forward the view that the education and training of young journalists must “rest on three central pillars: the priority of aptitudes and vocations; the certainty that investigation is not a professional speciality but that all journalism should, by definition, be investigative; and the awareness that ethics are not an occasional condition but should always accompany journalism like the buzz accompanies the blowfly.”"></Label>
		</parallax:Content>
	</parallax:ParallaxView>
</Page>